Hello everyone and welcome to chapter number 1.
In this chapter we are going to talk about what is mobile development.
Before we start coding, let's first understand what is the actual meaning of mobile development
and why it is very important.
So if I try to just simply write some while development.
means building apps or mobile devices. Got it? Whenever you wanted to build apps for
your mobile devices, like what are the name of mobile devices? It can be your smartphones.
It can be your tablets. You can even build apps for your IoT devices. But let's keep
that aside and only focus on these two. Perfect. Mobile development means,
building apps for mobile devices like your smartphones, your tablet, and these app.
Yes, these apps run on Android and iOS.
What are they?
They are just operating systems.
Perfect.
We are going to talk about it.
Don't worry.
And like if I just try to give you a bunch of examples of mobile apps that we have.
So, apps like we have a WhatsApp, we have Insta, we have YouTube, we also have Google
Maps, all of them are created.
Yes, all of them are created.
created using mobile development.
Yes, so yeah, same like you can even create your WhatsApp, Insta, YouTube, Google Maps,
all of them with the help of mobile development.
Perfect.
Now we understand what is mobile development, but why even mobile development matters?
So, today most time spent yes like today your 24 hour and out of your 24 hour you spend
more than 16 to 15 hours on your mobile phone perfect.
So, most people spend more time on their phones than on laptops.
Like we use mobile phones for if I just simply try to write here the purpose we are using
it for, for chattings, perfect, for shopping we can even use for payments, yes, we use
for learning like watching YouTube, watching Udemy courses and lot of other things as well.
You can even use your phone for watching.
your web series and just for anime and entertainment purpose got it so spend
more time on their phone rather than on laptops so these are the purpose you are
choosing for you can use for chatting shopping payment learning entertainment
and like anything
So, that's why companies need mobile app and they need mobile developer.
Perfect.
So, mobile development, if I just simply write here mobile development is untapped market
like no one is focusing on the mobile development as compared to web development like we have
a lot of web developers.
We don't have much mobile developers.
Perfect. So the first thing is in high demand.
Yep. Mobile development is in very high demand.
This is a valuable skill. Like if you know how to develop an app,
you can even ship your own apps and start earning out of it.
A strong career option. Like if you wanted to start your career,
you can definitely go with mobile development.
Perfect, so this is what mobile development and why even need it.
Now before moving ahead I just wanted to talk about types of mobile apps that we have.
Perfect, so there are always three main type of mobile apps like if I just simply try to
write here.
three types of mobile apps. Perfect. So the first type of mobile app is known as native
apps. Perfect. What is native app? Native apps means built for only one platform. Now another
type for our mobile apps that we have is cross platform.
Let me simply write here.
This is your cross platform app and third one is known as hybrid app.
What is hybrid app?
Hybrid app means mostly web apps inside a web mobile app kind of.
So we can simply say this as hybrid app.
Perfect native apps that only run on one platform cross platform app means they like you have
one code base that work on both Android and iOS in the same way we have hybrid app like
this is easy to build but like they usually slower and they can even run in web they can
even run mobile.
We can say that kind of a.
progressive web apps but let's not focus there perfect.
So this is what mobile development is why do you need it and types of mobile apps we
have.
So what will you learn in this course?
You are going to learn the real world mobile apps like how you can create your own real
world mobile apps.
how you can talk to the APIs that we have, how you can basically implement authentication,
how you can implement the mapping feature using camera using notifications like you
just name the topic and we are going to cover all of that inside this course.
Now one of the biggest questions that arise who is this course is for?
So, this course is for the complete beginners.
Like if you have the basic knowledge of JavaScript and React, like this is course, this course
is for you.
Then we have, if you are a web developer, you can definitely start with it.
If you are a student or working professional, you can definitely go with it.
So anyone who wants to build real mobile app, this course is for you.
Perfect.
So, yeah, this is pretty much it for the introduction of what is mobile development from next chapter.
We are going to talk about a bunch of other topics as well.
So, yeah, this is pretty much it and see you next time.